General Manuscripts Miscellaneous Collection, 1502-2012: Finding Aid C0140
Manuscripts Division
- McAllister, Samuel Ward, 1827-1895, 1864; McAllister, Ward, 1827-1895; 1 box (Box 32)
  ALS to unknown recipient, 16 May 1864.
- McArthur, John, 1805; M'Arthur, John, 1755-1840; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 11295
  ALS to Melville, Robert Dundas concerning Berlvand de Moleville's plan for a counter-revolution in France, 19 January 1805.
- McCaffrey, Phillip, undated; McCaffrey, Phillip, 1945-; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 2004-092
  ALS to Stanley Kunitz, n.d.
- McCall, R. H., 1986-1988; McCall, Robert, 1919-2010; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 2014-12
  R. H. McCall: 1 ALS (1988) and 1 TLS (1987) to "Mrs. Marks," TLS with essay (1986) to Lawrence Danson; Lawrence Danson: 1 TL (copy, 1986) to McCall in reply.
- McCarthey, Joseph Raymond, 1908-1957, 1954; McCarthy, Joseph, 1908-1957; 1 box (Box 32)
  Newspaper clippings, 1954. From an unknown collection
- McCay, Leroy Wiley, 1857-1927, 1912-1934; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 14328
  TMs, 97 limericks, 1912-1934.
- McClean, Henry, undated; 1 box (Box 32)
  D, execution of judgment against him in NJ court, n.d.
- McClelland, Robert, 1807-1880, 1855; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 17484
  Photostat of ALS, unaddressed, 23 August 1855.
- McClintock, Andrew Todd, 1845-1850; McClintock, Andrew Todd, 1885-1923; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 18136
  4 ALsS to McClintock from various correspondents, 1845-1850.
- McClintock, Samuel, Class of 1751, 1801; Macclintock, Samuel, 1732-1804; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 15095
  4 ALS to "Revd. Sir," 18 November 1801; AMs, n.d.
- McClung, J. W, 1858; McClung, J. W. (John W.); 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 11007
  DS to William M. Scott, deed for land in Cawes Co. Minnesota, 29 June 1858.
- McComb, John, 1789; McComb, John, 1773-; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 9006
  ALS to Robert Stockton, his brother-in-law, regarding financial matters between them, 16 November 1789.
- McConnell, William, 1833-1867, undated; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 91-19
  12 ALsS, illustrated, to Dr. Frisch (various spellings), n.d.
- McCook, John James, Trustee 1892-1906, 1882; McCook, John James, 1843-1927; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 8382
  LS to Henry Clay Cameron, 17 July 1882.
- McCormick, Cyrus H., 1859-1936, 1909; McCormick, Cyrus H. (Cyrus Hall), 1859-1936; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 12535
  TLS to Wilson Farrand regarding his election as an Alumni Trustee, 8 May 1909; TLs regarding a misunderstanding around this election, 1909.
- McCormick, Cyrus H., 1859-1936, 1915-1931; McCormick, Cyrus H. (Cyrus Hall), 1859-1936; 1 box (Box 32)
  TL to Mrs. S. Parsons regarding a borrowed manuscript, 17 March 1931; TLS from Stella Drumm, 16 March 1915.
- McCormick, Harold Fowler, 1872-1941, 1909; McCormick, Harold F. Harold Fowler 1872-1941; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 12531
  LS to Lynford Biddle regarding his attitude towards erecting another building for sports, May 1909.
  McCormick, Harold F. Harold Fowler 1872-1941
  The youngest son of Cyrus McCormick, inventor and manufacturer of the harvest reaper, Harold F. McCormick graduated from Princeton in 1895. Later that year on November 26, he married Edith Rockefeller, daughter of Standard Oil tycoon John D. Rockefeller, in Chicago, Illinois. In 1935 he became chairman of the board of International Harvester Company. McCormick later divorced Edith and married opera star Ganna Walska, whose career he lavishly promoted. Over many years, McCormick donated a number of important and rare materials to the Princeton University Library.
- McCormick, Harold Fowler, 1872-1941, 1930-1956; McCormick, Harold F. Harold Fowler 1872-1941; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 77-70, 18921
  Telegram from Mrs. Brightwell regarding a photograph album for auction, 25 October 1930; 2 TLs regarding McCormick, December 1956.
- McCosh, James, 1811-1894, 1851-1886; 1 box (Box 58)
  AM 10845
  diploma from Aberdeen, Scotland, March 5, 1851; diploma from the Queen's University, Ireland, 1863; diploma from Harvard, July 25, 1886.
- McCulloch, John Ramsay, 1789-1864, 1846; McCulloch, J. R. (John Ramsay), 1789-1864; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 13341
  ALS to J. T. Gibson Craig, 24 January 1846. Removed from Orlando Weber's copy of McColloch's "A Dictionary Geographical, Statistical and Historical," London, 1841-42.
- McDowell, David, 1725; McDowell, David L., 1956-; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 1533 Pyne Henry
  ALS to a merchant in London, 31 January 1725.
- McDowell, Joseph, 1838; McDowell, Joseph N. (Joseph Nash), 1805-1868; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 1763
  DS to James Stevenson, account vs. the estate of John D. Hart, 15 July 1838.
- McDuffie, George, 1790-1831, undated; McDuffie, George, 1790-1851; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 12665
  ANS, n.d.
- McFall, Frances Elizabeth Clarke, 1854-1943, 1906; MacFall, Frances Elizabeth 1854-1943; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 16546
  ALS to Mr. Stoker, 18 July 1906.
- Mchelm, John, 1785-1830; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 18258
  2 ALsS from John Modgens, 1785-1786; ALS to Cowen, 2 September 1807; invitation to the Examination of the Grammar-School at Trenton Academy, 2 April 1785; invitation to the Annual Commencement Ball of the College of New Jersey, 1830.
- McHenry, James, 1753-1816, 1813; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 13695
  ALS to Benjamin Fallmadge narrating a political dream, 15 January 1813.
- McHenry, James, 1753-1816, 1809; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 13697
  "A Dream," AMs, narrating a political dream, 4 March 1809.
- McIlvain, Bloomfield, Class of 1814, 1821; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 14595
  ALS to Philip R. Fendalls, 26 September 1821.
- McIlvaine, Charles P., 1799-1873, 1850-1855; McIlvaine, Charles Pettit, 1799-1873; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 128 Pyne Henry
  ALS to "My Dear Bishop" regarding church matters, 9 February 1850; ALS to "Rev. and Dear Sir," regarding giving communion that day, November 1855.
- McIntosh, Lachlan, 1725-1806, 1777; 1 box (Box 32)
  Typewritten transcript of letter to Colonel John Laurence describing circumstances of a duel in which he killed Button Gwinnett, 30 May 1777.
- McKenna, Joseph, 1843-1926, undated; McKenna, J. (Joseph), 1843-1926; 1 box (Box 32)
  Autograph signature, n.d.; engraving, n.d.
- McKenney, Thomas Loraine, 1785-1859, 1824-1826, 1829; McKenney, Thomas L. (Thomas Loraine), 1785-1859; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 2013-65
  17 autograph letters and articles by Thomas L. McKenney, Superintendent of Indian Affairs, most addressed to publisher Peter Force, on a variety of subjects, including Indian affairs and politics, 1824-1826, with typed transcriptions; 1 ALS by Peter Force to McKenney, with AN by McKenney, with typed transcription; 1 ALS (1829) by "Macdonald" about McKenney.
- McKesson, John, Class of 1753, 1777; McKesson, John, 1734-1798; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 259 Pyne Henry
  ADS, extracts from the minutes of the Committee of Safety for the State of New York, 1 March, 1777.
- McKinley, Ida, 1847-1907, undated; McKinley, Ida Saxton, 1847-1907; 1 box (Box 32)
  ACS to Mrs. Hayes, accepting her invitation for Wednesday noon, n.d.
- McKinley, John, 1780-1852, 1831; 1 box (Box 32)
  ALS to "Sir," 29 February 1831; engraving, n.d.
- McKinley, John, 1780-1852, undated; 1 box (Box 32)
  ALS to "Gentlemen," n.d.
- McKinley, William, 1843-1901, 1882-1896; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 9877-9881
  4 LsS to J. Hervey Cook, 1882-1896; ALS to Chief Justice Waite introducing Cook, 1882.
- McKinley, William, 1843-1901, 1 box (Box 32)
  2 ADsS regarding court cases in Ohio, n.d.; C, "Inauguration of the President," 1901.
- McKinley, William, 1843-1901, 1883; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 12187
  ALS to J. Harvey Cook thanking him for congratulations, 5 February 1883.
- McKinley, William, 1843-1901, 1899; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 11337
  DS to John R. Myrick, commission appointing him Lieutenant Colonel of Artillery, signed by McKinley and Elihu Root, Secretary of War, 26 December 1899.
- McKnight, Charles, 1750-1791, undated; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 8559
  Ms, biographical sketch, n.d.
- McLane, V, 1774; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 8980
  AD (fragment), survey of lands in Bedford Co., PA, belonging to Nicholas Rittenhouse, 9 August 1774.
- McLellan, Isaac, 1806-1899, 1890-1897; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 78-14
  2 ALsS to Charles Hallock, 27 April and 24 October 1897; ALS to "Dear Sir," 22 April 1890.
- McMillan, Henry Lyndon, Class of 1894, 1948; McMillan, Henry G; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 16079
  DS, diploma certifying McMillan became a member of the Society of Civil Engineers, 1 January 1948.
- McMurrin, Sterling M., 1914-1996, undated; McMurrin, Sterling M.; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 79-108
  "Brigham H. Roberts," TMs, notes on a Mormon philosopher-historian, n.d.
- McMurtrey, John, 1816; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 11818
  DS, certificate of the NJ Militia signed by Mahlon Dickerson, 22 June 1816.
- McNamara, Robert C., Jr, 1981; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 82-37
  ALS to Eleanor Lippincott, 23 November 1981.
- McPherson, David et al., 1816; McPherson, David et al; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 1904
  DS, 22 June 1816.
- McWhorter, Alexander, 1734-1807, 1800; Macwhorter, Alexander, 1734-1807; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 11286
  ALS to Andrew Kirkpatrick recommending John Croes for the position of Principal of a grammar school in New Brunswick, 14 July 1800.
- McWhorter, Alexander, 1734-1807, undated; Macwhorter, Alexander, 1734-1807; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 1234 Nelson
  AD, autograph copy of title page and contents of Volume 3 of his serious of sermons, n.d.
- McWhorter, Alexander, 1734-1807, 1783; Macwhorter, Alexander, 1734-1807; 1 box (Box 32)
  AM 11287
  ALS to John Croes, 16 August 1783. AM 11287
- Mead, Amos, 1788-1793; 1 box (Box 33)
  ADs, miscellaneous receipts, 1788-1793.
- Meade, William, 1789-1862, 1808-1810; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 9513-9523
  11 ALsS to Samuel L. Howell, many discussing life at Princeton, 1808-1810.
- Meade, William, 1789-1862, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 130 Pyne Henry
  ALS to Henry A. Wise regarding the home of George Washington, n.d.
- Meason, Isaac, 1798; Meason, Isaac, 1742-1818; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 12840
  ADS, appointment as Captain in the Nassau Blues, the military association of Princeton students, signed Alfred H. Powell, 2 August 1798.
- Mécs, László, 1895-1978, 1937; Mécs, László; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 82-82
  "Three Sorrows of the Prince," TMs, poem, translated by Pál Kelemen, 1937. Found in autographed copy of Pál Kelemen "Battlefield of the Gods: Aspects of Mexican History," Art and Exploration, London 1937. AM 82-82
- Meddaugh, James Edward, Photograph Taken at Holy Cross Episcopal Church, Pine Ridge Indian Reservation, 1890; Meddaugh, James Edward; 1 folder (Box 33)
  Purchased from Auger Down Books in 2021 (AM 2021-082).
  Consists of an albumen cabinet card photograph taken by James Edward Meddaugh, a white photographer based in Rushville, Nebraska, during a trip to Holy Cross Episcopal Church, Pine Ridge Indian Reservation, likely in the period just prior to the Wounded Knee Massacre. A handwritten caption on the mount reads: "Mr. Cook and his keepers, and some of the church people." The photograph depicts a group of several dozen subjects, most of whom appear to be Lakota people, standing and sitting in front of the church. Reverend Charles Smith Cook (Yankton Sioux, shown far left), is pictured, as are possibly Charles Eastman (Santee Dakota, shown fifth from the left) and Elaine Goodale Eastman (shown at the far right). The other people in the picture are probably the members of the congregation, alongside other missionaries and agency officials, and likely a policeman.
  Lakota Indians -- South Dakota -- History -- 19th century.; Pine Ridge Indian Reservation (S.D.) -- Photographs.; Albumen prints; Cabinet photographs; Church of the Holy Cross (Pine Ridge, S.D.); Cook, Charles S. (Charles Smith), 1855-1892; Eastman, Charles Alexander, 1858-1939; Eastman, Elaine Goodale, 1863-1953
- Medicis, Catherine de, 1519-1589, undated; Catherine de Médicis, Queen, consort of Henry II, King of France, 1519-1589; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 10813
  Photostat of ALS to Elizabeth of Spain, n.d. Photostat negative of the original in possession of Tertius Van Dyke, class of 1908, as of 1934.
- Meek, W. B, 1883-1914; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 79-176
  "Reminiscences of W. B. Meek of Camptonville, California," TMs, 1883-1914.
- Meem, Andrew Russell, 1841; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 12995
  AD, bill for accounts at Princeton, with ALS from Addison White, 1841.
- Melbourne, William Lamb, Viscount, 1779-1848, 1827-1835; 1 box (Box 33)
  3 ALsS to various correspondents, 1827-1835; 2 copies of engravings, n.d.
- Mellon, Andrew William, 1855-1937, 1924; Mellon, Andrew W. (Andrew William), 1855-1937.; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 18263
  TLS to Edward L. Howe, 22 January 1924.
- Melvill, Thomas, 1751-1832, 1803-1825; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 122 Pyne Henry, 248 Pyne Henry
  ALS to Samuel L. Southard asking that his grandson be appointed midshipman, 25 April 1825; DS, certificate of importation of one pipe of brandy, 6 June 1883.
- Melvill, Thomas, 1751-1832, 1826; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 20169
  ADS, relating to the schooner "Lion," 8 July 1826.
- Melville, Henry Dundas, Viscount, 1742-1811, 1809; Dundas, Henry, 1742-1811; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 11385
  ALS from the Duchess of Manchester, 13 December, 1809.
- Melville, Herman, 1819-1891, undated; Melville, Herman, 1819-1891.; 1 box (Box 33)
  Melville, Herman, 1819-1891.
  Herman Melville was an American novelist and storywriter. Not financially successful from his writings, he held the position of customs inspector for the City of New York for nineteen years. Moby-Dick, or The Whale, published in 1851, is today considered one of the masterpieces of American and world literature.
- Melvin, Howard, 1934; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 12654
  2 ALsS to Francis Estoy, 1934; clipping, 5 May 1934.
- Mencken, Henry Louis, 1880-1956, 1924-1936; Mencken, H.L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 92-1
  6 TLsS to Dr. Cramp, 1924-1936; TLS to Fishbein, n.d.; 10 TLs (Xerox) to Mencken, 1924-1936.
  Mencken, H.L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956
  H. L. (Henry Louis) Mencken (1880-1956) was an American journalist, magazine editor, critic, satirist and essayist. He was born in Baltimore and lived there all his life, and was known as the "Sage of Baltimore." He started his writing career as a journalist at the Baltimore Morning Herald, from 1899 to 1905, and then moved to The Baltimore Sun, where he contributed full-time until he suffered a stroke in 1948. In 1908, he became a literary critic for the magazine The Smart Set, and in 1924, he and George Jean Nathan founded The American Mercury. Dent Smith was founder and editor of the Hoboken-based literary magazine ENCORE between 1942 and 1944.
- Mende, Elsie Porter, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 17540
  ALS to Mr. Ludlaw, n.d.
- Mendeleff, Victor, 1885; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 19136
  ALS to Benjamin Hamblin, 26 May 1885.
- Menelik II, 1844-1913, 1900; Menelik II, Negus of Ethiopia, 1844-1913; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 9617
  ALS to Lord Gromer acknowledging 2 books in Arabic found in mosque in Khartum, 7 June 1900.
- Menninger, Karl Augustus, 1893-1990, 1949; Menninger, Karl A. (Karl Augustus), 1893-1990.; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 79-153
  TLS to Richard M. Ludwig regarding the publication of the Mental Health Conference materials, 7 June 1949.
- Menzies, Richard, 1974; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 21471
  TLS to Alfred Bush regarding the Salt Flat News, 22 March 1974.
- Mercer, Charles Fenton, 1778-1858, 1829; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 256 Pyne Henry
  ALS to John Symington accompanying receipts for a patent rifle, 2 February 1829.
- Mercer, Hugh, 1725-1777, 1754-1766; Mercer, Hugh, approximately 1725-1777; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 8047, 14903
  ALS with Photostat to unknown recipient, 6 November 1776; Photostat of ALS to James Burd, 10 July 1754.
- Mercer, Hugh, Jr., 1776-1853, 1847; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 8045, 8046
  2 ALSsS to Mrs. Caroline Crawford discussing his father and Princeton, 5 July and 6 August 1847.
- Mercer, Hugh, Jr., 1776-1853, 1840; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 15015
  ALS to Reverend Dodd, 29 April 1840.
- Mercereau, David, 1829; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 10598
  2 DsS to Mary W. Olden and David Worth, admitting them as guardians of Joseph and Susan W. Olden, 9 December 1829.
- Mercier de Saint-Léger, Barthélemy, 1734-1799, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 1998-67
  "Voltaire," AMs, n.d.
- Mercier, Désiré Joseph, 1851-1926, 1918-1919; Mercier, Désiré, 1851-1926; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 14883
  ALS from Louis Ayman Christian, 5 December 1918; ALS to Christian, 21 January 1919.
- Merrick, D, 1852; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 21992
  ALS to A. A. Mayer, 29 July 1852.
- Merrick, Leonard, 1864-1939, 1920; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 12878
  ALS to Mr. Maurice, 28 June 1920.
- Mershon, Grace Lucile Olmstead, undated; Mershon, Grace Lucile Olmstead, 1879-1974; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 2005-65
  "Oath of Allegiance of New Jersey Residents Administered February 1777," TMs, n.d.
- Merwin, Henry Childs, 1853-1929, 1925; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 18051
  ALS to Charles D. Allen, 3 February 1925. Letter found in book, 25 March 1964: in Mr. Clark's boxes.
- Methvin, John Jasper, 1846-1941, 1926; Methvin, J. J.; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 14152
  TLS to H. L. Scott, regarding his book on Indian territory, 6 October 1926.
- Metzerott, Oliver, 1918; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 14111
  D, appointing Metzerott a Regent of Maryland State University, 4 May 1918.
- Mexico: Jesuit Mission, 1778; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 20554
  "Mission de San Joseph de Matape," AMs in Spanish, inventory of the properties in Matape, 22 May 1778.
- Meyer, Charles E, 1888; 1 box (Box 33)
  ALS to Lambert, 8 June 1888.
- Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
- Meynell, Alice, 1847-1922, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 12631
  5 ALsS to Mrs. Warren, friendly letters mentioning several of Meynell's publications, n.d.
- Michelet, Jules, 1798-1874, 1867; Michelet, Jules, 1798-1874.; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 86-132
  ALS, in French, to unknown friend, recommending a young artist and architect, 9 April 1867.
- Michener, James Albert, 1907-1997, 1984; Michener, James A. (James Albert), 1907-1997; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 87-27
  TMs, unedited introduction to Ernest Hemingway's "Dangerous Summer," 48 pp., 1984.
- Mierow, Charles Christopher, 1883-1961, 1951; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 14454
  "Publication of 43 Years: Bibliography of Charles Christopher Mierow," TMs, 9 June 1951.
- Milbanke, Anne Isabella, 1792-1860, undated; Byron, Anne Isabella Milbanke Byron, Baroness, 1792-1860; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 20319
  ALS to "Elizabeth," n.d.
- Miford, Humphrey Sumner, 1877-1952, 1943; Milford, Humphrey Sumner, Sir, 1877-1952.; 1 box (Box 33)
  TLS to L. P. Smith regarding Smith's "Words and Days," 23 June 1943.
- Millais, Effie, 1828-1897, undated; Millais, John Everett, 1829-1896; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 20436
  ALS to Payne, n.d.
  Millais, John Everett, 1829-1896
  ohn Everett Millais was painter and illustrator and one of the founders of the Pre-Raphaelite Brotherhood. His daughter Effie was one of his favorite models.
- Mill, John, 1830; Mill, John Stuart, 1806-1873.; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 8030
  ALS to Edmund Morfund, 13 November 1830.
- Miller, Andrew, Photographs of Juliana Anaya de Glass and John T. Glass, circa 1886-1887; Miller, Andrew; 1 folder (Box B-001559, Folder 13)
  Purchased from Cowan's Auctions in 2021 (AM 2021-65).
  Consists of two cabinet card photographs picturing Juliana Anaya de Glass and John T. Glass, Chief of Scouts, of Fort Apache, Arizona, which were likely taken by Andrew Miller in Globe, Arizona. Both are studio portraits, one depicting both John and Juliana, and one depicting Juliana alone. John T. Glass was an African American soldier from the 10th Cavalry Regiment of the United States Army, who served as Chief of Scouts at Fort Apache, a United States military post on the lands of the White Mountain Apache people. While the photographs' captions refer to John Glass by name and indicate that the woman pictured is his wife, she is unnamed but has been identified elsewhere as Juliana Anaya de Glass and is likely an Apache woman.
  African American soldiers -- West (U.S.) -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Apache women -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Fort Apache (Ariz.); Cabinet photographs; Glass, John T.; Glass, Juliana Anaya de
- Miller, Henry, 1891-1980, 1937-1960; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980.; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 14767
  ALS to John Gunsworth, 7 October 1937; ALS to Dr. Ashley, 20 January 1960; ALS to Bern Porter, 22 January 1945; printed materials, n.d.
- Miller, Joaquin, 1841-1913, 1884; Miller, Joaquin, 1837-1913; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 82-76
  "May," AMs, poem, 1884. Removed from an album of a young lady. AM 82-76
- Miller, John Roberts, Class of 1863, 1861; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 14405
  ALS to "Sister," 10 November 1861.
- Miller, Nathan L., 1868-1953, 1921; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 9058
  Photostat of DS, proclamation regarding observance of 4 November as anniversary of the signing of the Armistice by Italy and Austria in the World War, 25 October 1921.
- Miller, Neville, 1894-1977, 1950; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 13909
  TLS to Julian Boyd regarding the Class of 1916, 27 April 1950.
- Miller, Neville, 1894-1977, 1916; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 13979
  AMs of speech given as Presentation Orator at Cannon Exercises, Commencement, 1916.
- Miller, Samuel Freeman, 1816-1890, 1867-1889; Miller, Samuel Freeman, 1816-1890.; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 22043
  3 ALsS to "Mr. President," 1869-1884; ALS to Major Poore, 17 December 1884; autograph signature, n.d.; copy of engraving, 1889; AMs, court notes on the Clinton Bridge, 1867.
- Miller, William, 1782; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM Winaus 4037
  DS, last will and testament, 1782; DS, signed by William Livingston, 11 February 1782.
- Mills, W. Jay, 1903; Mills, Weymer Jay, 1880-1938; 1 box (Box 33)
  ALS to J. Lawrence Boggs concerning William Paterson, Class of 1763, 12 March 1903.
- Milman, Henry Hart, 1791-1868, 1828; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 20314
  ALS to Joseph Blanco White advising him against starting a new review, 18 September 1828.
- Milne, Alan Alexander, 1883-1956, 1903; Milne, A.A. (Alan Alexander), 1882-1956; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 17920
  ALS to "Dear C. S.," 15 August 1903.
- Milne, Robert, Letters to Alexander Milne from Cape Henry, Haiti, 1813 July 18-1814 February 4; Milne, Robert; 1 folder (Box B-001559, Folder 18)
  Purchased from Wayfarer's Bookshop in 2021 (AM 2021-076).
  Consists of two lengthy letters from British coffee merchant Robert Milne in Cape Henry, Haiti, to his brother Alexander Milne during the years of the Kingdom of Haiti (1811-1820). The letters provide Milne's account of the coffee trade in Haiti, including information about prominent British and American merchants active there. He also mentions his plans to dispatch a ship called Louisa with a cargo of coffee to London, an audience with King Henri Christophe (1767-1820), the Palace of Sans-Souci, relationships between local Haitians and European foreigners, and the king's policies of perusing private correspondence and confiscating newspapers.
  Haiti -- Commerce -- History -- 19th century -- Sources.; Coffee industry -- Haiti -- History -- 19th century -- Sources; Henri Christophe, King of Haiti, 1767-1820
- Milner, Isaac, 1750-1820, 1807; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 8790
  ALS to John Barnwell Campbell concerning a testimonial, 9 September 1807.
- Milnes, Richard Monckton, Baron Houghton, 1809-1885, undated; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 79-85
  ALS to Sumner Jones, Jr. expressing his thanks for the poems he received, n.d.
- Minard, D. E., Letter to John E. Pomfret, 1934 October 16; Minard, Duane E. (Duane Elmer), 1880-1964, collector; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 2016-64
  Letter from Minard of Wawonaissa Farm, Boonton, New Jersey, concerning items relating to the history of Pennsylvania, New Jersey, and Delaware that he loaned to Pomfret.
  Minard, Duane E. (Duane Elmer), 1880-1964, collector
  Duane E. Minard was an American lawyer and assistant attorney general for the state of New Jersey.
- Minto, Mary, 1823; Minto, Mary Caroline, Countess of, 1858-1940; 1 box (Box 33)
  AM 11973
  Copy of ADS in which she legally frees her slave, Jane, 14 August 1823.